<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Some Things Float</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.SomeThingsFloat</packageId>
  <author>Mlie</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/SomeThingsFloat</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.4</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    <li>UnlimitedHugs.AllowTool</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/iCj5o7O.png[/img]

Let the river wash your trash away!

This mod lets things float in water and move with the stream. In non-streaming water things will move about at random. Things can leave the map this way so can be used to dispose of things you dont want, corpses for example.

There is a possibility that things spawn in the river that you can get use of, or even downed pawns you can choose to rescue. If [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=761421485]Allow Tool[/url] is active you can set all spawning items to be hauled urgently automatically. 

There is also bars and nets that can be built in water. The bars can catch large objects like corpses, living pawns, weapons and apparel while the metal net can catch all items.

Pawns may also loose their footing in moving water. They can also drown if being downed in water. Certain apparel will prevent this, such as the power-armor helmet. Any headgear with the EVA-tag from SOS2 will be considered a breathable helmet.

If [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1542399915]SwimmingKit[/url] is loaded, pawns with higher swimspeed will float slower when downed. Also pawns with the Nimble trait will be half as likely to loose their footing.

Technically the mod looks at all items in water-tiles and calculates their floating value. This is based on what stuff is used to build the item, but some things like corpses have a default float value. Its also possible to add floatable-values to other things via patches, there is a patch for barrels of fecal-matter from [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=836308268]Dubs Bad Hygiene[/url] that can be used as an example. Higher floatable values makes things move quicker in the water.

I made it mostly for my own playthrough but hopefully someone else can get joy from it!

[table]
    [tr]
        [td][url=https://dsc.gg/mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td]
        [td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/SomeThingsFloat][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
    [tr]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/WjDSfUn.png[/img][/td]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/Be8E2qJ.png[/img][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]

[img]https://i.imgur.com/Ds0rBAD.png[/img]
Since modding is just a hobby for me I expect no donations to keep modding. If you still want to show your support you can gift me anything from my [url=https://store.steampowered.com/wishlist/id/Mlie]Wishlist[/url] or buy me a cup of tea.

[url=https://ko-fi.com/G2G55DDYD][img]https://i.imgur.com/VWG0yff.png[/img][/url]

[img]https://i.imgur.com/5xwDG6H.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[/list]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/2940072380]Last updated 2023-04-13[/url]</description>
</ModMetaData>